<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<author-reprints xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <sec>
        <p>
            <graphic xlink:href="../../../../../../journal-images/author-reprints/author-reprints.jpg"/>
        </p>
        <break/>
        <p><bold>Bentham Science provides excellent professionally printed reprints, each inside a beautiful journal cover, which you can proudly send to colleagues and scientists in your field. In this connection please find below an electronic view of the reprint cover. These reprints with cover are available at concessionary rates.</bold></p>
    </sec>
    <break/>

<sec>

<table>
    <tr>
    <td style="border: 1px solid black; text-align:justify; padding-right: 20px; padding-top: 20px; padding-left:20px; font-size: 16px;">
    <p>You may wish to benefit from a special limited time package that we can offer with your order of minimum 100 reprints / e-prints of the article. On the placement of your order, you will be entitled to avail a special package which includes:</p>
    <break/>
  
    <list list-type="bullet">
                <list-item>
                    <p><bold>35%</bold> discount, in case you now decide to order a minimum of <bold>100 reprints</bold> of your article.</p>
                </list-item>
                 </list>
              <break/>
                <list list-type="bullet">
                <list-item>
                    <p><bold>25%</bold> discount on <bold>Open Access Plus</bold> charges, in case you now decide to order <bold>25, 50,75 or 100 reprints</bold> of your article.</p>
                </list-item>
                </list>
                <break/>
                <list list-type="bullet">
                <list-item>
                    <p><bold>Free promotion</bold> of your article through a special press release on major news websites like <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-01/bsp-ftt011516.php">EurekAlert</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/">Science Daily</uri> &#x0026; <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.onwardhealthcare.com/medical-express-redirect/">Medicalxpress</uri> etc.</p>
                </list-item>
            </list>
    
    </td>
       </tr>
    
    </table>
</sec>
    
    <sec>
        <title>SPECIAL OFFERS</title>
        <p>
            <list list-type="numeric">
                <list-item>
                    <p>Authors who order minimum <bold>100 or below reprints</bold> will be entitled to a <bold>25% discount</bold> on the “<bold>Open Access Plus</bold>” publication fee.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>Authors who order minimum <bold>200, 300, 400</bold> and <bold>500</bold> will be entitled to a <bold>50% discount</bold> on the “<bold>Open Access Plus</bold>” publication fee.</p>
                </list-item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </sec>
    <sec>
        <title>COLORED REPRINTS</title>
        <p>If the article was originally printed in color, the reprint will be an exact replication of the original for an additional charge.</p>
    </sec>
    <sec>
        <title>COMPANY LOGO</title>
        <p>Company logos and foreword can be published on the printed reprint cover page in sponsored reprints.</p>
   </sec>
    <sec>
        <title>500 OR MORE REPRINTS</title>
           <p>All authors ordering 500 or more reprints will be entitled to have that article made open access at a 50% discount. This will save you substantial funds and lead to increased visibility and readership.</p>
     <p>We will offer a 30% discount voucher against each reprint order which will be applicable on the next reprint order and valid for 12 months.</p>
     <p>Orders Above 500 reprint copies: A quotation for orders above 500 can be obtained by emailing at <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="reprints@benthamscience.net">reprints@benthamscience.net</email>.</p>
     </sec>
    <sec>
        <title>PRINTED COVERS</title>
        <p>Printed covers are available at extra cost.</p>
            </sec>
            
            <sec>
        <title>AIRMAIL AND HANDLING COSTS</title>
        <p>Reprints are dispatched to the customers by airmail. Airmail and handling costs will be invoiced additionally with the reprints. Our shipping department requires the name and telephone number of the recipient of the order. These quotes are in US Dollars and are valid for 30 days.</p>
            </sec>
            
            <sec>
        <title>SHIPPING INSTRUCTIONS</title>
        <p>Once confirmed, your order will ship to deliver in 35 business days from the day the proofs, if required, have been approved or from the day of confirmation. Expedited delivery option is also available.</p>
            </sec>
</author-reprints>