<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<author-benefits>
    <front>
        <heading>Bentham Science Publishers (BSP) is recognized for publishing quality peer-reviewed STM journals and eBooks.</heading>
        <title>Bentham Science Publishers offers article contributors a number of benefits:</title>
    </front>
    <benefits-list>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>SUBMIT MANUSCRIPTS EASILY</title>
                <p>Manuscripts can be submitted online through a simple process using the BSP Content Management System.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>EXPERIENCE AUTHENTIC PEER REVIEW</title>
                <p>All submitted manuscripts are peer- reviewed by expert reviewers. Bentham Science Publishers follows the single blind peer-review procedure for submission of all manuscripts to its journals in order to ensure that research content meets ethical and scientific quality standards.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>GET EDITORIAL ASSISTANCE</title>
                <p>BSP’s  experienced editorial and journal staff assist authors in the management, proofreading, and copy editing of submitted manuscripts prior to publication. All efforts are made to ensure that rigorous peer review and pre-publication procedures are done as professionally and as quickly as possible.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>TRACK YOUR ARTICLE'S PROGRESS</title>
                <p>Authors may track their articles at anytime during the peer-review procedure via the BSP Content Management System.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
            	<title>AVOID PLAGIARISM</title>
                <p>Bentham Science Publishers uses iThenticate<sup>&#x00AE;</sup> to detect any instances of overlapping of submitted content with any existing published material. </p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>FREE MONTHLY EMAIL ALERTS</title>
                <p>Free monthly updates can be provided through BSP’s  journal Table of Content (TOC) alerts and article alerts allowing scientists to keep up-to-date with BSP’s publications.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>EPUB AHEAD OF PRINT</title>
                <p>The EPub Ahead of Print facility allows author’s research to be published online before it is published in the print edition of a journal.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>MAKE YOUR RESEARCH MORE ACCESSIBLE</title>
                <p>Authors may avail BSP’s Open Access publication option at a reasonable fee and share their research to a potentially large number of scientists worldwide.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>OBTAIN ARTICLE REPRINTS</title>
                <p>BSP provides high quality article reprints with free printed covers, ideal for presentation to authors’ colleagues and collaborators.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>INCREASE YOUR SEARCHABILITY THROUGH INDEXATION SERVICES</title>
                <p>BSP journals are indexed by major abstracting and indexing media including <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://thomsonreuters.com/en/products-services/scholarly-scientific-research/scholarly-search-and-discovery/science-citation-index-expanded.html">Science Citation Index Expanded (SciSearch<sup>&#x00AE;</sup>)</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://thomsonreuters.com/en/products-services/scholarly-scientific-research/research-management-and-evaluation/journal-citation-reports.html">Journal Citation Reports/Science Edition</uri>, Index to Scientific Reviews<sup>&#x00AE;</sup>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://thomsonreuters.com/en/products-services/scholarly-scientific-research/scholarly-search-and-discovery/web-of-science.html">Web of Science</uri>, Biotechnology Citation Index, Biochemistry &#x0026; Biophysics Citation Index<sup>&#x00AE;</sup>, Prous Science Integrity, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://thomsonreuters.com/en/products-services/scholarly-scientific-research/scholarly-search-and-discovery/biosis-citation-index.html">BIOSIS</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://thomsonreuters.com/en/products-services/scholarly-scientific-research/scholarly-search-and-discovery/biosis-previews.html">BIOSIS Previews</uri>, BIOSIS Reviews Reports and Meetings, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/">Index Medicus / MEDLINE</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.scopus.com/">Scopus</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.embase.com/">EMBASE</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.cas.org/">Chemical Abstracts</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.biobase-international.com/">BIOBASE</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.pubshub.com/">PubsHub</uri>, Scirus, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.who.int/hinari/en/">Hinari</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://journalseek.net/">GenamicsJournalSeek</uri>, <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.mediafinder.com/">MediaFinder<sup>&#x00AE;</sup>-Standard Periodical Directory</uri> and <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://jgateplus.com/search/login/">J-Gate</uri>.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>AVAIL DISCOUNTS ON JOURNAL SUBSCRIPTIONS AND EBOOKS</title>
                <p>Contributors can receive discounts on Bentham Science publications through BSP’s online store for journal articles and eBooks. </p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>UTILIZE MULTIMEDIA CONTENT</title>
                <p>Authors may present their published research with BSP also in video (podcast) format and blogs, helping to disseminate published results to a wider audience.</p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
        <benefit-entry>
            <sec>
                <title>EXPAND YOUR PRESENCE</title>
                <p>BSP’s marketing team partners can assist authors in promoting and sharing their research through various social media platforms, thus providing an opportunity to network with both academic and industrial professionals around the world. </p>
            </sec>
        </benefit-entry>
    </benefits-list>
</author-benefits>