<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<author-guideline>
    <sec>
        <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
        <p>Bentham Science Publishers publishes over 100 journals (print and online) and an extensive library of eBooks in science, technology, medicine, and social sciences.</p>
        <p>A digital marketing approach is actively used by Bentham Science to increase awareness among end-users of all published content. This approach includes complete website accessibility, search engine advertising, blogging, search engine optimization, social networking, affiliate marketing, and online press releases.</p>
        <p>Besides the use of these online marketing tools, Bentham Science also promotes their publications at various events including scientific conferences and publishing tradeshows worldwide.</p>
        <p>
            <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A1.jpg"/>
        </p>
    </sec>
    <sec>
        <title>BSP HOMEPAGE</title>
        <sec>
            <title>JOURNAL HOMEPAGES</title>
            <p>All research journals have their own dedicated homepages. The homepages can be easily searched by journal and article names.  From the company homepage visitors can access the various journal homepages.</p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A2.jpg"/>
            </p>
            <p>Journal homepages provide the following:
<list list-type="bullet">
<list-item>
<p>Aims and Scope</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Instructions for Authors</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Abstracted/Indexed in</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Ranking</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>About the Editorial Board</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Full access to current and all volumes and issues</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Editor’s Choice articles</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Open Access Articles</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Related journals and eBooks</p>
</list-item>
</list>
</p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>EDITOR’S CHOICE</title>
            <p>The Editorial Board has an important role to assist with the solicitation, submission and peer -review of manuscripts. All submitted manuscripts are peer-reviewed usually by independent experts in the field in association with members of the journal editorial board. The editorial board and Editor-in-Chief help to ensure that the highest publication standards and ethics are maintained.</p>
            <p>The <italic>Editor’s Choice</italic> section on every journal’s homepage contains a selection of articles exclusively nominated by the Editor-in-Chief as important and noteworthy. These selected articles are promoted on the Bentham Science website and on all the relevant social media pages. </p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A3.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>OPEN ACCESS PLUS</title>
            <p>Through the <italic>Open Access Plus</italic> option, authors of papers accepted for publication can opt for a fee to have their articles published as open access. Readers do not need to subscribe to the journal to view open access content. </p>
            <p>Bentham Science offers a 40% discount on open access fees to its editorial board members and those authors who have contributed more than two articles in Bentham Science journals. </p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A4.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>ARTICLES BY DISEASE</title>
            <p>
                <italic>Articles by Disease</italic> is Bentham Science’s online platform for searching Bentham Science published articles by disease class. Access to the ‘Articles by Disease’ tab is via the Bentham Science homepage.  All relevant articles published in Bentham Science journals qualify for complimentary listing in this useful and popular database. </p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A5.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>SEARCH ENGINE OPTIMIZATION (SEO)</title>
            <p>Search Engine Optimization, or SEO, is a technique used to make content easily accessible through search engines like Google, Yahoo etc. It enables the link for any webpage or content to appear ahead of other links for the same keywords when searched on a search engine. </p>
            <p>We request our authors to provide their preferred keywords which are relevant to their research publications. When users search for specific keywords that match with their research, SEO makes it more likely that the article appears in the search results.  </p>
            <p>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>HIGHLIGHTED ARTICLE FLYERS</title>
            <p>Highlighted article flyers (print and electronic editions) are brochures that focus on a specific article or group of articles based on a theme. These flyers serve as promotion for our authors for distribution at relevant conferences and to their research colleagues and to other contacts in the field. </p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A6.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
    </sec>
    <sec>
        <title>SPECIALIZED PLATFORMS FOR RESEARCH PROMOTION</title>
        <sec>
            <title>BSP ARTICLES ON ACADEMIA</title>
            <p>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://Academia.edu">Academia.edu</uri> is a platform for academicians in order to share their research papers. Academicians use <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://Academia.edu">Academia.edu</uri> to share their research findings, monitor deep analytics around the impact of their research, and to keep updated with regards to the research of academics they follow. Over 32 million academicians have signed up for Academia.edu, adding over 7.5 million papers. Academia.edu attracts over 36 million unique visitors a month. A recent study found that papers uploaded to <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://Academia.edu">Academia.edu</uri> receive a 73% boost in citations over 5 years (Source: Price <italic>et al., Open Access Meets Discoverability: Citations to Articles Posted to <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://Academia.edu">Academia.edu</uri></italic>).</p>
            <p>Bentham Science manages various accounts on Academia.edu, which include corporate as well as journal and ebook specific accounts. In this way, author’s research abstracts and papers are readily made available in a huge database to fellow researchers worldwide.</p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A7.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>BSP PARTNERSHIP WITH KUDOS</title>
            <p>Kudos is a web-based service that helps researchers and their institutions and funders to maximize the visibility and impact of their published articles. Kudos provides a platform for assembling and creating information to help searching and sharing research, and for measuring and monitoring the effect of these activities. The objective is to increase the discoverability of new or related research publications.</p>
            <p>Bentham Science has now partnered with Kudos to reach out to the growing community of researchers, institutions and publishers signing up on the Kudos network. In this way, author’s published research helps to get more acknowledged among a wider net of  researchers who access the Kudos networking platform.</p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A8.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>BSP NEWS via EUREKALERT!</title>
            <p>
                <italic>EurekAlert!</italic> is an online, global news service operated by the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS). <italic>EurekAlert!</italic> provides a central medium through which universities, medical centers, government agencies, corporations and other organizations engaged in research can bring their important research discoveries to the media. It also offers its news and resources to the public. The service features news and resources focused on all areas of science, medicine and technology.</p>
            <p>Authors publishing in Bentham Science journal, can issue a press release for <italic>EurekAlert!. EurekAlert!</italic> In particular has a strong readership base in the USA.  </p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A9.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
    </sec>
    <sec>
        <title>SOCIAL MEDIA TO PROMOTE YOUR RESEARCH</title>
        <p>
            <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/social-media-main.php">http://benthamscience.com/social-media-main.php</uri>
        </p>
        <p>BSP uses social media channels to help disseminate and promote author’s research findings.  The following are regularly shared through social media of author’s published work:
<list list-type="bullet">
<list-item>
<p>recent published articles</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>highlighted articles</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>press releases from authors</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>videos</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>contributors’ testimonials</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>call for papers</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>informative blogs</p>
</list-item>
</list></p>
        <p>All of these activities help the published work to reach a larger global audience and to provide an opportunity to increase the discoverability and citations of the work. Bentham Science can share information about their author’s published work on a variety of social media networking sites as summarized below.</p>
        <sec>
            <title>BENTHAM SCIENCE ON YOUTUBE</title>
            <p>YouTube, being the most visited video-streaming website, proves to be an extremely effective mode of promotion. Bentham Science has its own channel on YouTube, featuring videos and presentations helping to promote further published research articles and eBooks unique to Bentham Science. The channel also provides our authors a valuable opportunity to describe their research work to their global target audience. Authors can also use YouTube videos to provide additional content that can supplement or complement their published work.</p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A10.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>BENTHAM SCIENCE FACEBOOK PAGES</title>
            <p>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.facebook.com/BenthamSciencePublishers">www.facebook.com/BenthamSciencePublishers</uri>
            </p>
            <p>Bentham Science uses Facebook for bringing the outstanding efforts of our authors to the forefront. The Facebook pages are divided into the following categories. 
<list list-type="bullet">
<list-item>
<p>BSP Corporate page</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Subject area pages</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Journal pages</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Diseases specific pages</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Region-wise pages</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>eBook page</p>
</list-item>
</list></p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A11.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>BSP LINKEDIN PAGES</title>
            <p>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/bentham-science-publishers">https://www.linkedin.com/company/bentham-science-publishers---uae</uri>
            </p>
            <p>LinkedIn is a formal network suitable for sharing updates for topics relating to all professions. This makes it perfect for Bentham Science to convey information to a professional audience tailored to specific research content. Bentham Science regularly share news, articles, podcasts and other important information with followers of Bentham Science LinkedIn pages. Many researchers, authors and editors have joined Bentham Science’s LinkedIn pages and are expanding the reach of their articles and books by sharing relevant information with their LinkedIn network peers.</p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A12.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>BENTHAM SCIENCE MICROBLOGS ON TWITTER</title>
            <p>twitter.com/BenthamScienceP<uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://twitter.com/BenthamScienceP">twitter.com/BenthamScienceP</uri></p>
            <p>Twitter has emerged as a highly trusted resource for sharing rapid news and highlights through microblogs. Bentham Science helps to reach a wide audience via three separate accounts:
<list list-type="bullet">
<list-item>
<p>Corporate profile</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>EBooks profile</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>High Impact Factor journals’ profile</p>
</list-item>
</list></p>
            <p>The authors and editors can connect with Bentham Science and communicate about their articles and eBooks through tweets and retweets.</p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A13.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>BENTHAM SCIENCE NEWSLETTER</title>
            <p>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://benthamsciencepublishers.wordpress.com/">https://benthamsciencepublishers.wordpress.com/</uri>
            </p>
            <p>Bentham Insight is the official newsletter of Bentham Science publishing the latest updates, articles, research, news, testimonials, reviews, offers, information for upcoming journals and eBooks every day. Bentham Insight serves as a way to communicate to its readers about the latest developments in science. Bentham editors and article authors can also contribute to this blog to engage their audience.  </p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A14.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
    </sec>
    <sec>
        <title>EVENTS AND CONFERENCES</title>
        <sec>
            <title>BENTHAM SCIENCE AND CONFERENCES</title>
            <p>Bentham Science regularly attends and displays with an exhibition booth at a number of important scientific conferences and library trade events internationally. Such events provide an opportunity to interact wih Bentham Science staff and with attending Bentham Science journal editorial board members and book authors. Conference attendees also have access to Bentham Science content displayed and exclusive offers.  Typically available at Bentham Science exhibition booth are the following: 
<list list-type="bullet">
<list-item>
<p>Banners promoting journals and books</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Sample copies of journals and books</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>CDs containing scopes, abstracts and information of the articles and authors</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Flyers and catalogs  for journals and books</p>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<p>Giveaways</p>
</list-item>
</list></p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A15.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>CONFERENCE PROMOTIONS</title>
            <p>Conference promotions are complimentary cross-pomotional partnerships between Bentham Science Publishers, and conference organizations as well as some institutions. These marketing exchanges allow each party to promote their brands; providing  access to a larger target audience. </p>
            <p>
                <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/author-guideline/A16.jpg"/>
            </p>
        </sec>
    </sec>
</author-guideline>
