<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<bsp-content xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <sec>
        <p>
            <graphic xlink:href="../../../../../../journal-images/bsp-content/bsp-content.jpg"/>
        </p>
        <p>Bentham Science, since its inception, has been striving to reach all of its stakeholders in the most convenient ways possible. In this modern era, publications can be accessed through various different means, whether online or in printed form. Hence, through our technological expertise, we provide you with maximum possible secure alternatives, so that no barrier stands in the way of accessibility.</p>
		<p>Following are the different means through which we make publications accessible to you conveniently and securely.</p>
    </sec>
   	 <sec>
        <title>Various Online Publication Formats</title>
        <p>
            <list list-type="bullet">
                <list-item>
                    <p><bold>HTML, PDF, ePub</bold> – Our content is available in HTML, PDF and ePub formats for convenience of readers.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p><bold>Mobile version</bold> – Our websites are optimized for usage through smartphones / cellphones from anywhere around the world.</p>
                </list-item>
				<list-item>
                    <p><bold>Tablet formats</bold> – Content is also accessible through pocket-friendly formats, <italic>i.e.</italic> ePub, Kindle, <italic>etc.</italic>, for e-readers or tablets.</p>
                </list-item>
            </list>
        </p>
    	</sec>
	
	    <sec>
        <title>Worldwide Availability of Content</title>
        <p>
            <list list-type="bullet">
                <list-item>
                    <p><bold>Databases indexation</bold> – Bentham Science journals are abstracted / indexed in major indexing agencies worldwide. Most notably: Science Citation Index®, Journal Citation Reports/Science Edition, Science Citation Index Expanded, Index to Scientific Reviews®, Biochemistry and Biophysics Citation Index®, Current Contents® - Life Sciences, Research Alert, BIOSIS, Prous Science Integrity®, MEDLINE/PubMed/Index Medicus, Scopus, EMBASE/Excerpta Medica, Chemical Abstracts Service/SciFinder, ProQuest, ChemWeb, Google Scholar, BIOBASE, Reference Update, PubsHub, Index Copernicus, MediaFinder®-Standard Periodical Directory, Genamics JournalSeek, J-Gate, CNKI Scholar, Suweco CZ, TOC Premier, EBSCO, British Library, Ulrich's Periodicals Directory, JournalTOCs, <italic>etc.</italic></p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p><bold>Reach of our content</bold> – Our content is securely sent to our existing suppliers, <italic>i.e.</italic> CAS, PUBMED, LINKOUT/PUBMED, SCOPUS, CCC's Content Services, JST, SUWECO, Infotrieve Inc., Edanz, FID, FIZ Auto Doc, Inform India (Research Gate), Ex Libris' Primo Central, CrossRef/CROSSCHECK, EBSCO A to Z, <italic>etc.</italic>, in order to increase the reach of our content globally.</p>
                </list-item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </sec>

	<sec>
        <title>Ease of Readers</title>
        <p>
            <list list-type="bullet">
                <list-item>
                    <p><bold>Graphical abstracts</bold> – Graphical abstracts (optional) can be viewed for articles in order to have a brief picture of what the articles comprise of.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p><bold>Most cited and most accessed articles</bold> – Most cited and most accessed articles of each journal can be viewed under every journals’ homepages.</p>
                </list-item>
				<list-item>
                    <p><bold>Related Article(s)</bold> – Under each article’s details, viewers can find the “Related Article(s)”. This feature provides quick access to relevant material of not just Bentham Science journals, but other publishers’ journals as well. This is powered by our partner TrendMD.</p>
                </list-item>
				<list-item>
                    <p><bold>Alerts</bold> – Our Table of Contents (TOC) alerts and Rich Site Summary (RSS) feeds help readers to stay updated with our content as per their requirements.</p>
								<list list-type="bullet">
								<list-item>
								<p>Simple search of our content is available (with auto-completion).</p>
								</list-item>
								<list-item>
								<p>Advanced search is available with filters on subject category, journal / E-Book, title, abstract, keywords, authors, full-text, years (“from” and “to”), ISSN and ISBN.</p>
								</list-item>
								<list-item>
								<p>Expert search is also available and this contains “Boolean” and “Proximity” search modes.</p>
								</list-item>
								</list>
				</list-item>
				<list-item>
                    <p><bold>Social networks</bold> – Links to the most popular social media sites (LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter, <italic>etc.</italic>) can be found at various places on our websites.</p>
                </list-item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </sec>
	
	
	
	
    <sec>
        <title>Open Access Publications</title>
        <list list-type="bullet">
		<list-item>
		<p><bold>Open Access Option</bold> – Authors can make their manuscripts freely accessible to readers through this facility. An “Open Access” bar is displayed against each article, in order to differentiate them from other charged articles.</p>
		</list-item>
		</list>
    </sec>
    
	<sec>
        <title>Access Control of Content</title>
        <list list-type="bullet">
		<list-item>
		<p><bold>Access control</bold> – Control over access is maintained through specific IP addresses. Users gain access through secure login credentials, <italic>i.e.</italic> username and password.</p>
		</list-item>
		<list-item>
		<p><bold>Pay-per-view (PPV)</bold> – Using the PPV function, articles can be accessed by non-subscribers.</p>
		</list-item>
		</list>
    </sec>
	
	<sec>
        <title>Preservation of Data and Global Compatibility</title>
        <list list-type="bullet">
		<list-item>
		<p><bold>Long-term data preservation</bold> – For most of Bentham Science journals, we preserve our content through trusted and secure third-party organizations, such as Portico, PubMed Central, IngentaConnect, <italic>etc.</italic></p>
		</list-item>
		<list-item>
		<p><bold>DOI</bold> – Digital Object Identifier (DOI) is a sequence of numbers, letters and symbols that is used to identify an article / document and to link to it to the internet. Bentham Science collaborates with International DOI Foundation to assign each article a specific DOI, in order to help researchers cite articles and to conform to global standards.</p>
		</list-item>
		<list-item>
		<p><bold>ISSN (Print) / ISSN (Online)</bold> – A specific International Standard Serial Number (ISSN) ID in the form of ISSN (print) and ISSN (online) is assigned to each journal. This ID helps researchers to differentiate the journals, and to cite any articles of those journals.</p>
		</list-item>
		<list-item>
		<p><bold>ISBN</bold> – A specific International Standard Book Number (ISBN) ID is assigned to each book. This ID helps to differentiate the books.</p>
		</list-item>
		<list-item>
		<p><bold>CrossRef</bold> – Bentham Science is a member of CrossRef, which is an authorized Digital Object Identifier (DOI) Registration Agency of International DOI Foundation.</p>
		</list-item>
		<list-item>
		<p><bold>Global Compatibility</bold> – Bentham Science conforms to global standards through its collaborations with major institutions, <italic>i.e.</italic> DOI, CrossRef, CrossCheck, <italic>etc.</italic></p>
		</list-item>
		</list>
    </sec>
</bsp-content>