<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<corporate-sale>
    <sec>
        <title>Bentham Science Corporate Sales</title>
        <p>As one of the world&#x2019;s major STM publishers, here at Bentham Science, we publish in excess of 100 highly respected online and print peer-reviewed journals. We also publish a fast growing collection of ebooks. Since 1993, we have been supporting the educational needs of the pharmaceutical, engineering, biomedical and medical research community.</p>
        <sec>
            <title>Create awareness of your Brand and reach your target audience</title>
            <p>Through a variety of print and electronic formats we can help you to deliver a marketing strategy for your brand.</p>
            <list list-type="bullet">
                <list-item>
                    <p>
                        <bold>Reprints &#x0026; ePrints</bold> – Highlight your brand with an article or chapter reprint in either print or electronic format and lend kudos with publication branding.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>
                        <bold>Themed Collections</bold> – Reinforce your message with a collection of articles in branded livery.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>
                        <bold>Supplements</bold> – Build Brand awareness, deliver cutting edge information, and support educational needs, with a peer reviewed supplement circulated with one of our highly regarded journals.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>  
                    <p>
                        <bold>Newsletters</bold> – Deliver your important message quickly with one of our subject specific &#x201C;Key Views&#x201D; newsletters, delivered direct to your target audience, via one or more of our peer reviewed journals.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>
                        <bold>Sponsored subscriptions</bold> – Increase visibility by providing valuable clinical content to your target audience.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>
                        <bold>Books</bold> – A range of options including bulk orders, ePrints and translations.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>
                        <bold>Custom publications</bold> – Help build relationships with bespoke branded publications.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>
                        <bold>Advertising</bold> – Build brand awareness with targeted flexible print or online advertising options.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>
                        <bold>Translations</bold> - Extend the reach of your product, service or brand, we can offer you a comprehensive translation service.</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>
                        <bold>Webinars and Podcasts</bold> – Sponsored webinars and Podcasts allow in depth engagement with experts and key opinion leaders globally.</p>
                </list-item>
            </list>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>Why choose Bentham Science</title>
            <list list-type="bullet">
                <list-item>
                    <p>High impact factor journals</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>Disease specific publications</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>Endorsements from Nobel Laureates and Eminent Scientists</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>Global subscribers</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>Well known editorial boards (KOL&#x2019;s)</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>Medline Indexing</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>Dedicated Account Manager</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>Excellent customer service and  efficient project management</p>
                </list-item>
                <list-item>
                    <p>Expedited project timelines available</p>
                </list-item>
            </list>
            <p>
                <bold>To discuss your requirements please contact</bold>
            </p>
            <table cellspacing="1" width="100" border="0">
                <tr>
                    <td>Faizan ul Haq</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Email: <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="faizan@benthamscience.net">faizan@benthamscience.net</email></td>
                    <td>Tel: +44 (0) 7921 837044</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </sec>
    </sec>
</corporate-sale>