<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<endorsement>
    <endorsement-body>
        <endorsement-list>
            <display-quote>
                <display-quote-image>ferid.gif</display-quote-image>
                <p>"<bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-medicinal-chemistry/#top">Current Medicinal Chemistry</uri></bold> is a leading journal in the field of medicinal chemistry where cutting edge reviews in hot topic areas are regularly published. It provides scientists in the field with comprehensive review articles written by experts and eminent researchers in the field and allows them to keep abreast with the latest developments in the field. The journal is highly recommended to all scientists in the field of medicinal chemistry".</p>
                <attrib>Ferid Murad</attrib>
                <awards-list>
                    <award>
                        <bold>The Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine (1998) and the Albert Lasker Award for Basic Medical Research (1996)</bold> For their discoveries concerning nitric oxide as a signalling molecule in the cardiovascular system</award>
                </awards-list>
                <aff>University of Texas Medical School-Houston Texas, USA</aff>
            </display-quote>
            <display-quote>
                <display-quote-image>robert.gif</display-quote-image>
                <p>"<bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-medicinal-chemistry/#top">Current Medicinal Chemistry</uri></bold> is a frontier review journal, which contains comprehensive reviews written by leading scientists in their respective fields. The journal presents the latest developments in various areas of medicinal chemistry. I strongly recommend it to scientists working in the field."</p>
                <p>"<bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-genomics/#top">Current Genomics</uri></bold> represents a frontier review journal, which contains comprehensive reviews written by leading scientists in the respective fields. This journal presents the latest developments in the area of genomics. This is strongly recommended."</p>
                <p>"The 4 new journals <bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/recent-patents-on-anti-cancer-drug-discovery/#top">Recent Patents on Anti-Cancer Drug Discovery</uri></bold>, <bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/recent-advances-in-cardiovascular-drug-discovery/#top">Recent Patents on Cardiovascular Drug Discovery</uri></bold>, <bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/recent-patents-on-cns-drug-discovery/#top">Recent Patents on CNS Drug Discovery</uri></bold>, <bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/recent-patents-on-anti-infective-drug-discovery/#top">Recent Patents on Anti-Infective Drug Discovery</uri></bold> are important patents journals in the field of Anti-Cancer Drug Discovery, Cardiovascular Drug Discovery, CNS Drug Discovery and Anti-Infective Drug Discovery, which should provide research scientists in the fields with recent developments in various frontier areas. These journals are strongly recommended to the scientific community". </p>
                <attrib>Robert Huber</attrib>
                <awards-list>
                    <award>
                        <bold>The Nobel Prize in Chemistry 1988</bold> For the determination of the three-dimensional structure of a photosynthetic reaction centre.</award>
                </awards-list>
                <aff>Max-Planck-Institut für Biochemie Martinsried, Martinsried, Germany</aff>
            </display-quote>
            <display-quote>
                <display-quote-image>jean-marie.gif</display-quote-image>
                <p>"In view of the growing volume of literature, the role of a high quality review journal has become increasingly important. <bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-medicinal-chemistry/#top">Current Medicinal Chemistry</uri></bold> presents expert overviews in the field of medicinal chemistry of general interest to the scientific community."</p>
                <p>"In view of the growing volume of literature, the role of high quality review journals has become increasingly important. <bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-drug-targets/#top">Current Drug Targets</uri></bold> is an important journal in the field of medicinal chemistry and drug design, which is strongly recommended to the scientific community."</p>
                <p>"<bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/mini-reviews-in-medicinal-chemistry/#top">Mini-Reviews in Medicinal Chemistry</uri></bold> represents an important review journal of great value to pharmaceutical scientists."</p>
                <p>"<bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-topics-in-medicinal-chemistry/#top">Current Topics in Medicinal Chemistry</uri></bold> is recommended as a forum for the publication and review of important aspects of medicinal chemistry including the design and synthesis of compound libraries for bioactivity testing."</p>
                <attrib>Jean-Marie Lehn</attrib>
                <awards-list>
                    <award>
                        <bold>The Nobel Prize in Chemistry 1987</bold> For the development and use of molecules with structure-specific interactions of high selectivity.</award>
                </awards-list>
                <aff>Universit&#x00E9; Louis Pasteur Strasbourg, France</aff>
            </display-quote>
            <display-quote>
                <display-quote-image>james.gif</display-quote-image>
                <p>"<bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-topics-in-medicinal-chemistry/#top">Current Topics in Medicinal Chemistry</uri></bold> provides medicinal chemists and scientists in allied disciplines an invaluable resource for thematic coverage of keen new developments in their field of study."</p>
                <attrib>(Late) Sir James W. Black (1924 – 2010)</attrib>
                <awards-list>
                    <award>
                        <bold>The Nobel Prize in Physiology 1988</bold> For the discoveries of important principles for drug treatment</award>
                </awards-list>
                <aff>London University, King&#x0027;s College Hospital, London, U.K</aff>
            </display-quote>
            <display-quote>
                <display-quote-image>derek.gif</display-quote-image>
                <p>"<bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-medicinal-chemistry/#top">Current Medicinal Chemistry</uri></bold> represents an important review journal of great value to medicinal chemists in universities and pharmaceutical industries."</p>
                <p>"<bold><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-organic-chemistry/#top">Current Organic Chemistry</uri></bold> is an important chemistry review journal, which will present frontier reviews in organic chemistry. The journal will prove to be a very useful source of up-to-date information. The eminent international stature of the Guest Editors will guarantee the high standards expected of an international journal."</p>
                <attrib>(Late) Sir Derek H. R. Barton (1918 - 1998)</attrib>
                <awards-list>
                    <award>
                        <bold>The Nobel Prize in Chemistry 1969</bold> For the development of the concept of conformation and its application in chemistry.</award>
                </awards-list>
                <aff>Imperial College, London, U.K. </aff>
            </display-quote>
            <display-quote>
                <display-quote-image>herbert.gif</display-quote-image>
                <p>
                    <bold>"<uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-medicinal-chemistry/#top">Current Medicinal Chemistry</uri></bold> has established itself as an important review journal in the field of medicinal chemistry. It provides research scientists in the field with comprehensive review articles written by eminent experts. It allows them to keep abreast with the latest relevant developments. The journal is highly recommended to all scientists active in the field of medicinal chemistry."</p>
                <p>
                    <bold>"<uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.benthamscience.com/journals/current-organic-chemistry/#top">Current Organic Chemistry</uri></bold> is an important review journal, which should prove to be of wide interest to organic chemists and provide them with a convenient means of keeping up with the current flood of advances in the field."</p>
                <attrib>(Late) Herbert C. Brown (1912 - 2004)</attrib>
                <awards-list>
                    <award>
                        <bold>The Nobel Prize in Chemistry 1979</bold> For the development of the use of boron- and phosphorus-containing compounds, respectively, into important reagents in organic synthesis.</award>
                </awards-list>
                <aff>Purdue University, West Lafayette, USA</aff>
            </display-quote>
        </endorsement-list>
    </endorsement-body>
</endorsement>