<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<predatory-publisher xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <sec>
        <title>Is Bentham Science a Predatory Publisher?</title>
        <p>Although there is no exact definition for what constitutes a predatory publisher, predatory or deceptive publishing usually refers to a business model that involves charging publication fees to authors without pre-informing them of it and publishing manuscripts without checking articles for quality and legitimacy. <italic>Bentham Science has never engaged in predatory publishing, and uses a thorough vetting process to ensure each journal meets ethical and peer-review standards</italic>.</p>
        <p>Reputable publishers pursue proper ethics in publishing by focusing keenly on disseminating research information that can be trusted, is relevant for research, and is presented in ways to serve efficient knowledge transfer. These measures in return support quality research studies.</p>
        <p>So the question arises as to how can one identify whether a publisher is legitimate or is predatory? A publisher that fails to follow accepted standards or best practices of scholarly publishing is considered predatory.</p>
        <p>When it comes to quality publication, one of the best scholarly practices is to authenticate whether the information stated by the author is up to the mark or not through an independent peer-review process. The peer review process separates scientific conclusions from speculation. Simply stated, peer review increases and authenticates research quality.</p>
        <p>Each article submitted to Bentham Science (Subscription and Open Access) is rigorously peer-reviewed; often multiple times, and checked for plagiarism, in order to provide good quality information to those who are seeking it. Bentham’s publications are also part of COPE, an organization that aims to define best practice in the ethics of scholarly publishing and to assist authors, editors and publishers to achieve these defined standards. We have several notable journals included in the Journal Citation Reports of Clarivate Analytics with Impact Factor rankings as well.</p>
        <p>Bentham Science publishes over 140 scholarly journals (subscription based and open access) related to various subject areas of science, technology and medicine. The journals are indexed, recognized and associated with reputable scientific agencies, directories and other entities.</p>
        <p>Therefore, proposed authors and readers do not need to be concerned about the quality of our published research in any regard. Bentham Science stands against all kinds of predatory practices and at the same time has duly satisfied its stakeholders and maintained their trust and association.</p>
    </sec>
</predatory-publisher>