<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<press-release>
            <press-release-list>
                <press-release-entry>
                    <sec>
                    <title>EpiCongress London</title>
                    <p>On November 19<sup>th</sup> – 21<sup>st</sup> 2013 <bold>EpiCongress London </bold>will join scientific leaders from pharma, biotech and academia, all dedicated to accelerating drug discovery and development. The epigenetic community is coming together to share their unpublished data, secrets and most exciting epigenetic developments over the past year. Hear about the studies that are breaking new ground in the field, including HMT, demethylases, bromodomains and 2nd generation HDAC compounds. The agenda is packed full of practical information you can take away and incorporate into your own programmes, ensuring you can <bold>progress your epigenetic molecules through the pipeline, faster.</bold></p>
                    </sec>
                </press-release-entry> 
                <press-release-entry>
                    <sec>
                    <title>World Conference On Regenerative Medicine In Leipzig: Registration And Abstract Submission Now Open</title>
                    <p>The World Conference on Regenerative Medicine 2013 will take place from 23 – 25 October 2013 at the Congress Center Leipzig, Germany. Online Registration is now open at: www.wcrm-leipzig.com. Abstracts for oral and poster presentations can be submitted until 11 June on the conference website. The conference offers a discussion platform to different disciplines of Regenerative Medicine. (<uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="../journal-files/Call-for-Abstracts.pdf">click here for further details</uri>)</p>
                    </sec>
                </press-release-entry>  
                 <press-release-entry>
                    <sec>
                    <title>PHARM Connect: Pharma and Biotech professionals of CEE getting together for further industry growth in the region</title>
                    <p>Central and Eastern Europe is a rapidly emerging market for pharmaceutical manufacturing and distribution, and at the same time countries of the region are becoming hot-spots for research with many universities, research institutes and biotechnology companies being present. On the other hand, companies in the pharmaceutical sector face challenges that are not encountered in any other, from healthcare reforms to changing regulations. It is clear that in these sectors the constant search for effective and innovative partnerships as well as continuous professional development and market-specific knowledge are more important than in any other field. (<uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="../journal-files/Press-Release2013.pdf">click here for further details</uri>)</p>
                    </sec>
                </press-release-entry>              
            </press-release-list>
</press-release>