<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<self-archiving-policy>
    <sec>
        <title>SELF-ARCHIVING POLICIES</title>
        <p>By signing the Copyright Letter the authors retain the rights of self-archiving. Following are the important features of self-archiving policy of <italic>Bentham Science</italic> journals:
        <list list-type="order">
        <list-item>
        <p>Authors can deposit the first draft of a submitted article on their personal websites, their institution’s repositories or any non-commercial repository for personal use, internal institutional use or for permitted scholarly posting.</p>
        </list-item>
        <list-item>
        <p>Authors may deposit the ACCEPTED VERSION of the peer-reviewed article on their personal websites, their institution’s repository or any non-commercial repository such as PMC, arXiv after <bold>12 MONTHS of publication</bold> on the journal website. In addition, an acknowledgement must be given to the original source of publication and a link should be inserted to the published article on the journal's/publisher’s website.</p>
        </list-item>
        <list-item>
        <p>If the research is funded by NIH, Wellcome Trust or any other Open Access Mandate, authors are allowed the archiving of published version of manuscripts in an institutional repository after the mandatory embargo period. Authors should first contact the Editorial Office of the journal for information about depositing a copy of the manuscript to a repository. Consistent with the copyright agreement, <italic>Bentham Science</italic> does not allow archiving of FINAL PUBLISHED VERSION of manuscripts.</p>
        </list-item>
        <list-item>
        <p>The link to the original source of publication should be provided by inserting the DOI number of the article in the following sentence: “The published manuscript is available at EurekaSelect <italic>via</italic> http://www.eurekaselect.com/openurl/content.php?genre=article&#x0026;doi=[insert DOI].”</p>
        </list-item>
        <list-item>
        <p>There is no embargo on the archiving of articles published under the OPEN ACCESS PLUS category. Authors are allowed deposition of such articles on institutional, non-commercial repositories and personal websites immediately after publication on the journal website.</p>
        </list-item>
        </list></p>
    </sec>
</self-archiving-policy>