<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<terms-conditions>
    <sec>
        <title>Terms and Conditions:</title>
        <p>Please read this license agreement carefully before using this site. Any software, content or other material that is on this site is the copyrighted work of Bentham Science Publishers and/or its suppliers. This license agreement pertains to the use of this content. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not use this site. By using this site, you are showing your acceptance of these terms.</p>
        <sec>
            <title>Online subscriptions:</title>
            <p>Please note that the academic and corporate online subscription rate applies to one site access only.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>Archives:</title>
            <p>Please note that perpetual access is available to the paid and subscribed volumes.</p>
            <p>For purchase of back volumes please contact our subscription department for pricing and availability.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>Restrictions on use of the content:</title>
            <p>This site is owned and operated by Bentham Science Publishers. You may download sample copies on a single computer for personal or non-commercial temporary use, providing you take into account the copyright and any other trademark notices. No content however, may be copied, reproduced, distributed, republished or posted. If you download content from this site, the content remains licensed with Bentham Science Publishers.</p>
            <p>It is forbidden to republish or redistribute the content, including by framing or similar means, nor may the content be modified in any way or for any purpose as this constitutes a violation of the copyright of Bentham and/or its suppliers.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>Warranty disclaimer:</title>
            <p>The content in this site is provided "as is" and without warranties of any kind either express or implied. Bentham Science Publishers does not guarantee that the site will at all time function error free, or that the site or server are at all times virus free.</p>
            <p>Bentham Science Publishers does not guarantee the contents correctness, accuracy, reliability or otherwise.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec>
            <title>Liability disclaimer:</title>
            <p>No responsibility is assumed by Bentham Science Publishers, its staff or members of the editorial board for any injury and/or damage to persons or property as a matter of products liability, negligence or otherwise, or from any use or operation of any methods, products instruction, advertisements or ideas contained in this publication/CD-ROM. Any dispute will be governed exclusively by the laws of U.A.E. and will be settled exclusively by the competent Court at the city of Dubai, U.A.E.</p>
        </sec>
    </sec>
</terms-conditions>