<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
    <front>
        <journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <issn pub-type="ppub">
            </issn>
            <issn pub-type="epub">
            </issn>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
        <article-meta>
            <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20180802-003</article-id>
            <title-group>
                <article-title>Memorization test &#x0026; resting state EEG components in mild &#x0026; subjective cognitive impairment</article-title>
            </title-group>
            <aff id="aff1">
                <bold>Research article: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/161637/article">Memorization Test and Resting State EEG Components in Mild and Subjective Cognitive Impairment</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 18-JUL-2018</aff>
            <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
                <year>
                </year>
            </pub-date>
            <volume>
            </volume>
            <issue>
            </issue>
            <history>
                <date date-type="released">
                    <day>28</day>
                    <month>07</month>
                    <year>2018</year>
                </date>
            </history>
            <permissions>
                <copyright-year>
                </copyright-year>
            </permissions>
            <abstract>
                <p>
                    <italic>This article by Dr. Giulia Mazzon et al. is published in <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://benthamscience.com/journals/car/">Current Alzheimer Research</uri>, Volume 15, Issue 9, 2018</italic>
                </p>
            </abstract>
        </article-meta>
    </front>
    <body>
        <p>Researchers at the University of Trieste have found that using a nonlinear approach in EEG analysis in combination with a cognitive task during EEG recordings could make the difference in highlighting EEG alterations at very early stages of cognitive impairment. This EEG protocol may therefore be a practical and non-invasive tool in the clinical context to identify subjects for second level diagnostic examinations for Alzheimer&apos;s Disease (AD).</p>
        <p>Mild (MCI) and Subjective Cognitive Impairment (SCI) are conditions at risk of developing Alzheimer&apos;s disease. Differential between normal aging at early stages can be really challenging; available biomarkers need to be combined and can be quite invasive and expensive.</p>
        <p>The researchers recruited 11 MCI, 8 SCI and 7 healthy subjects as controls (CS), all matched for age and education; they performed neuropsychological assessment and EEG recording, at resting state and during a mental memory task, and they used both classical spectral measures and nonlinear parameters to characterize EEGs.</p>
        <p>During cognitive tasks, &#x03B1;-band power reduction was found predominantly in frontal regions in SCI and CS, diffused to all regions in MCI; moreover, decreased EEG complexity was found in SCI compared to controls. The &#x03B1;-band power attenuation restricted to frontal regions in SCI during a free recall task (involving frontal areas), suggests that MCI patients compensate for encoding deficit by activating different brain networks to perform the same task. Furthermore, EEG complexity reduction - that has been found already in SCI - could be a possible early hallmark of AD. The researchers suggest that this analysis may be applied in clinical routine as a diagnostic and prognostic tool in subjects with complaining of initial cognitive impairment.</p>
        <p>The study, &apos;Memorization test and resting state EEG components in mild and subjective cognitive impairment&apos;, co-authored by Giulia Mazzon and his collaborators, all of the University Trieste, was published recently in&#x00A0;Current Alzheimer Research.</p>
        <p>For more information about the research, please visit:&#x00A0;<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/161637">http://www.eurekaselect.com/161637</ext-link></p>
        <p>Reference: Mazzon G et al, (2018). Memorization Test and Resting State EEG Components in Mild and Subjective Cognitive Impairment.&#x00A0;Current Alzheimer Research, Vol 15, Issue 9. DOI: 10.2174/1567205015666180427114520</p>
    </body>
</article>
