<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
    <front>
        <journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
        <article-meta>
            <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20172012-005</article-id>
            <title-group>
                <article-title>Anti-tumor and immune-potentiating Enterococcus faecalis-2001 β-glucans</article-title>
            </title-group>
            <aff>
                <bold>Review Article: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/156062/article">Pharmaceutical Production of Anti-tumor and Immune-potentiating Enterococcus faecalis-2001 β-glucans: Enhanced Activity of Macrophage and Lymphocytes in Tumor-implanted Mice</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 13-DEC-2017</aff>
            <abstract>
                <p>This article by Dr. Yeun-Hwa Gu et al. has been published in <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://benthamscience.com/journals/cpb/">Current Pharmaceutical Biotechnology</uri>, Volume 18, Issue 8, 2017</p>
            </abstract>
        </article-meta>
    </front>
    <body>
        <p>
            <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://benthamscience.com/journal-images/recent-trend/RT-20172012-005.jpg"/>
        </p>
        <p>Background: Enterococcus faecalis 2001 is a probiotic lactic acid bacterium and has been used as a biological response modifier (BRM). From physiological limitation of bacterial preservation in storage and safety, the live E. faecalis 2001 has been heat-treated and the BRM components containing high level of &#x03B2;-glucan, named EF-2001, were prepared. Method: The heat-treated EF-2001 has been examined for the antioxidative potential for radical scavenging and anti-tumor activities as well as immune-enhancing response in mice. Lymphocyte versus polymorphonuclear leukocyte ratio was increased in mice upon treatment with EF-2001. The number of lymphocytes was increased in the EF-2001-treated group. In the mice bearing two different Ehrlich solid and Sarcoma-180 carcinomas, the treatment with EF-2001 resulted in anti-tumor action. Tumor-suppressive capacity upon treatment with EF-2001 was significantly increased compared to normal controls. Results: During the time interval administration of 5 weeks between the priming and secondary administration of EF-2001, the expression and production levels of TNF-&#x03B1; were also observed in the EF-2001administered mice. Additionally, anti-tumor activity examined with the intravenous administration of EF 2001 with a 34 time intervals was also observed, as the growth of Sarcoma180 cells was clearly inhibited by the EF-2001. Conclusion: From the results, it was suggested that the immune response is enhanced due to antioxidative activity caused by the EF-2001 and anti-tumor activity by NK cells and TNF-&#x03B1;.</p>
        <p>For more information about the article, please visit&#x00A0;<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/156062">http://www.eurekaselect.com/156062</ext-link></p>
    </body>
    <back>
        <p>Reference: Gu YH, et al. Pharmaceutical Production of Anti-tumor and Immune-potentiating Enterococcus faecalis-2001 β-glucans: Enhanced Activity of Macrophage and Lymphocytes in Tumor-implanted Mice . Current Pharmaceutical Biotechnology, 2017, Vol 18, Issue 8, DOI: 10.2174/1389201018666171002130428</p>
    </back>
</article>
