<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190402-003</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title>Bentham Science publishes eighth volume in clinical drug research -- Alzheimer disorders</article-title>
</title-group>
<aff>
                <bold>Book: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9789811401893/">Frontiers in Clinical Drug Research - Alzheimer Disorders</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 12-MAR-2019</aff>
<abstract>
<p>This book is edited by: Atta-ur-Rahman, published on: March 4, 2019</p>
</abstract>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<break/>
<p>Frontiers in Clinical Drug Research - Alzheimer Disorders is a book series concerned with Alzheimer&apos;s disease (AD), a disease that causes dementia, or loss of brain function. This disease affects parts of the brain that affect memory, thought, and language. Chapters in each volume focus on drug research with special emphasis on clinical trials, research on drugs in advanced stages of development and cure for Alzheimer&apos;s disease and related disorders.</p>
<break/>
<p><bold>About the Editor:</bold></p>
<p><bold>Prof. Dr. Atta-ur-Rahman</bold></p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Atta-ur-Rahman, Ph.D. in organic chemistry from Cambridge University (1968), has over 1080 international publications in several fields of organic chemistry including 751 research publications, 37 international patents, 69 chapters in books and 222 books published largely by major U.S. and European presses. He is the Editor-in-Chief of eight European Chemistry journals. He is Editor of the world's leading encyclopedic series of volumes on natural products, Studies in Natural Product Chemistry, 54 volumes of which have been published under his Editorship by Elsevier during the last two decades. For more information, Kindly visit: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9789811401893/">https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9789811401893/</ext-link></p>
</body>
</article>
