<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
        <article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190329-002</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://benthamscience.com/press-releases/19013001/">Editor-In-Chief of Current Microwave Chemistry receives ICS Life Time Achievement Award</ext-link></article-title>
</title-group>
<aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 5-FEB-2019</aff>

</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<p>Book: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086279/">Topics in Anti-Cancer Research</ext-link></p>
<p>Dr. Bimal K. Banik, currently the Editor-In-Chief of Current Microwave Chemistry, Current Organocatalysis and Open Chemistry Journal  receives the Life-Time Achievement Award 2018 from the Indian Chemical Society (ICS). The ICS was established by Sir Acharya P. C. Ray in 1924 and it is one of the oldest scientific societies in India and also in the world. The Life Time Achievement Award was inaugurated in 1999 and is awarded in recognition of outstanding contributions by chemistry researchers in the world. Dr. Banik is serving as the Vice President of Research &amp; Education Development of Community Health Systems of South Texas. He has been involved in research, teaching, mentoring, advising and administration in the USA for over 25 years. He was a Tenured Full Professor and President&apos;s Endowed Professor at the University of Texas-Pan American. Dr. Banik has been awarded multimillion dollar grants by NIH, NCI and other private research foundations as the Principal Investigator. Importantly, he has published and presented approximately 828 papers and patented several discoveries. His research interests include the synthesis and biological evaluation of natural and non-natural anticancer agents and antibiotics as well as catalytic methods, environmentally friendly chemical reactions and microwave-chemistry. Currently, he is also the Editor-in-Chief of 7 other journals. He has received several awards and recognitions for his outstanding research, teaching, advising, mentoring and academic service at the University, State, National, International and Public levels.</p>
<break/>
<p>For more information, please visit:  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.rsc.org/news-events/community/2019/jan/lifetime-achievement-award/">http://www.rsc.org/news-events/community/2019/jan/lifetime-achievement-award/</ext-link></p>
</body>
</article>
