<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190329-003</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title>A concise and visual reference diagnostic ultrasonography and biopsy of the thyroid gland</article-title>
</title-group>

            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 22-JAN-2019</aff>
<abstract>
<p>This book is by Dr. Samer El-Kaissi, and Dr. Jack R. Wall, Published on: December 11th, 2018.</p>
</abstract>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<sec sec-type="other1">
<break/>
<p>Book URL: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086859/">https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086859/</ext-link></p>
<break/>
<p><bold>ARTICLE:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086859/">Thyroid Ultrasonography and Fine Needle Aspiration Biopsy: A Practical Guide and Picture Atlas</ext-link></p>
<p>The book provides the reader essential information on how to 1) distinguish between normal and abnormal thyroid sonograms, 2) differentiate low suspicion for malignancy thyroid nodules from sonographically high suspicion nodules, 3) evaluate cervical lymph nodes and parathyroid glands, and 4) examine post-thyroidectomy patients with differentiated thyroid cancer. The reader is also introduced to the different thyroid nodule risk stratification systems in ultrasound imaging, when and how to perform thyroid fine needle aspiration biopsies, and the use of percutaneous ethanol injections for cystic thyroid nodules.</p>

<p><bold>Key Features:</bold></p>
<p>- 11 chapters which begin with an introduction to thyroid ultrasound and progressively explain relevant diagnostic imaging and biopsy procedures for different thyroid diseases (including thyroid cancer and autoimmune diseases)</p>
<p>- Multiple tables and figures which summarize and highlight important points</p>
<p>- More than 60 ultrasound images which illustrate various ultrasound signs and artefacts from patients</p>
<p>- A summary of the current standards for the evaluation and clinical management of thyroid nodules based on clinical practice guidelines</p>
<p>- A detailed list of references, abbreviations and symbols</p>
<p>The textbook is an essential reference for both practicing and training endocrine surgeons, endocrinologists, radiologists, cytopathologists, sonographers as well as any health care worker with an interest in managing thyroid and parathyroid diseases in their daily practice.</p>
<break/>
<p><bold>About the Author:</bold></p>
<p><bold>Dr. Samer El-Kaissi</bold></p>
<p>Dr Samer El-Kaissi is a Staff Physician in Endocrinology at Cleveland Clinic Abu Dhabi. He is a medical graduate from The Flinders University of South Australia and completed post-graduate training in Endocrinology at Barwon Health in Victoria, Australia. Dr El-Kaissi has been performing thyroid ultrasonography, thyroid fine needle aspiration and thyroid nodule alcohol ablation since 2003. He has taught thyroid ultrasound techniques and fine needle aspiration biopsy at multiple workshops.</p>
<p><bold>Dr. Jack R. Wall</bold></p>
<p>Prof Jack R Wall is a Consultant Endocrinologist at the Bays Hospital in Mornington Peninsula, Victoria, Australia and an adjunct Professor of Medicine at the University of Sydney, New South Wales, Australia. Prof Wall has a strong interest in thyroid disorders and performs in-office thyroid ultrasonography and fine needle aspiration biopsies. He has more than 200 peer-reviewed publications and has supervised numerous students and endocrine fellows and helped them develop their interest in thyroid disease research.</p>
<p>For more information, please visit: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086859/">https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086859/</ext-link></p>
</sec>
</body>
</article>
