<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190522-001</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title>APOE gene has a gender-based effect on sleep behavior of Alzheimer&apos;s disease patients</article-title>
</title-group>
<aff>
                <bold>Research article: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/168750/article">Abnormal Sleep Behaviours Across the Spectrum of Alzheimer’s Disease Severity: Influence of APOE Genotypes and Lewy Bodies</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 15-APR-2019</aff>
<abstract>
<p>This article by Dr. David G. Munoz is published in Current Alzheimer Research, Volume 16, Issue 3, 2019.</p>
</abstract>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
    <break/>

<p>The gene most often associated with risk of Alzheimer&apos;s Disease impacts sleep depending on gender and the severity of Alzheimer&apos;s in a patient, suggests a study led by researchers at the Keenan Research Centre for Biomedical Science (KRCBS).</p>
<p>Selected as an Editor&apos;s Choice article by Current Alzheimer Research, this work examined the relationship of abnormal sleep behavior to Apolipoprotein (APOE) &#x03B5;4 allele and to the lesions in the brain responsible for the symptoms of this disease. APOE &#x03B5;4 allele has previously been established as the major risk factor for Alzheimer&apos;s disease.</p>
<p>The findings suggest that one effect of this gene variant is to alter sleep prior to the development of Alzheimer&apos;s disease. These findings are consistent with previous evidence on the effect of this gene.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an important topic to explore further because sleep disturbances constitute a major disruption for caregivers of patients with Alzheimer&apos;s Disease,&quot; said Dr. David Munoz, project investigator at the KRCBS. &quot;It has also been proposed that alterations in sleep drive the development of Alzheimer&apos;s disease.&quot;</p>
<p>The researchers found the effects of the gene studied are seen in women only. In elderly patients without Alzheimer&apos;s disease, carriers of APOE &#x03B5;4 have significantly more nighttime disturbances than non-carriers.</p>
<p>As a next step, Dr. Munoz and his team will look into the timeline of sleep disturbances throughout the development of Alzheimer&apos;s, along with the timing of declines in cognitive testing.</p>

<p>For more information about the article, please visit</p>
<p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/168750/article">http://www.eurekaselect.com/168750/article</ext-link></p>
</body>
</article>
