<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190402-012</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title>'Thyroid Ultrasonography and Fine Needle Aspiration Biopsy: A Practical Guide and Picture Atlas'</article-title>
</title-group>
<aff>
                <bold>Book: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086859/">Thyroid Ultrasonography and Fine Needle Aspiration Biopsy: A Practical Guide and Picture Atlas</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 6-FEB-2019</aff>
<abstract>
<p>This book is by Dr. Samer El-Kaissi, and Dr. Jack R. Wall, published on: Dec. 11, 2018.</p>
</abstract>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<break/>
<p>Thyroid ultrasonography is the gold-standard of thyroid and cervical node imaging and can be seen as an extension of the physical examination. Learning how to perform thyroid ultrasound scans in the office or simply reading thyroid and neck ultrasound images is a great skill for practitioners to acquire. Thyroid Ultrasonography and Fine Needle Aspiration Biopsy: A Practical Guide and Picture Atlas provides essential information about the thyroid and anterior neck ultrasonography for both the novice and advanced thyroid disease practitioners.</p>
<p>This book contains 11 chapters that discuss the basic principles of ultrasound physics and sound waves, followed by a brief overview of anterior neck anatomy. Subsequent chapters focus on ultrasound imaging of the normal thyroid gland, nodular and autoimmune disorders of the thyroid, cervical lymph nodes and parathyroid glands. There is a dedicated chapter for ultrasound surveillance in post-operative thyroid cancer, and there are two chapters discussing procedures of the thyroid, namely fine needle aspiration biopsy of the thyroid and cervical lymph nodes, and percutaneous ethanol injection of cystic thyroid nodules.</p>
<p>Chapter VII discusses the clinical management of thyroid nodules with an easy-to-follow clinical algorithm [Figure 7]. Although not directly linked to ultrasound imaging of the thyroid, we felt this chapter would be useful for readers who are interested in the role of neck ultrasonography in the clinical setting. The chapter provides an updated overview of the current standard of care for patients with thyroid nodules using various thyroid nodule risk stratification systems including that of the American Thyroid Association, American College of Radiology TI-RADS and the European Thyroid Association&apos;s EU-TIRADS.</p>
<p>The text in this book is supported by 7 figures and 10 Tables to highlight salient points and facts. Most importantly, an ultrasound book would not be complete without ultrasound images and this book contains 66 real-patient ultrasound images to help illustrate various ultrasound signs and features. The ultrasound images can serve as a quick visual reference to look up specific ultrasound features while seeing patients or doing ultrasound scans.</p>
<p>After reading this book, the novice practitioner will have gained sufficient knowledge to start reading thyroid and anterior neck ultrasound images, and to begin performing their own thyroid ultrasound scans but of course the latter will take some practice. For the more advanced thyroid practitioner, this book reinforces their knowledge base, provides an update on thyroid ultrasonography and ultrasound-guided procedures, and allows them to fine tune their ultrasonography skills.</p>
<break/>
<p><bold>About the Author:</bold></p>
<p><bold>Dr. Samer El-Kaissi</bold></p>
<p>Dr Samer El-Kaissi is a Staff Physician in Endocrinology at Cleveland Clinic Abu Dhabi. He is a medical graduate from The Flinders University of South Australia and completed post-graduate training in Endocrinology at Barwon Health in Victoria, Australia. Dr El-Kaissi has been performing thyroid ultrasonography, thyroid fine needle aspiration and thyroid nodule alcohol ablation since 2003. He has taught thyroid ultrasound techniques and fine needle aspiration biopsy at multiple workshops.</p>
<p><bold>Dr. Jack R. Wall</bold></p>
<p>Prof Jack R Wall is a Consultant Endocrinologist at the Bays Hospital in Mornington Peninsula, Victoria, Australia and an adjunct Professor of Medicine at the University of Sydney, New South Wales, Australia. Prof Wall has a strong interest in thyroid disorders and performs in-office thyroid ultrasonography and fine needle aspiration biopsies. He has more than 200 peer-reviewed publications and has supervised numerous students and endocrine fellows and helped them develop their interest in thyroid disease research.</p>
<p>for further information please visit: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086859/">https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086859/</ext-link></p>
</body>
</article>
