<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.3" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
        <article-meta>

<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190329-001</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title>Bentham Science publishes new edition of Higgin's organ donation guide</article-title>
</title-group>
<aff>
                <bold>Book: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681087566/">The Multi-Organ Donor: A Guide to Selection, Preservation and Procurement</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 22-JAN-2019</aff>
<abstract>
<p>This book is by Dr. Robert S. D. Higgins, and Dr. Juan Sanchez, published on Nov. 29, 2018</p>
</abstract>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<p>The lifesaving potential of transplantation has been limited by the number and quality of appropriate organ donors. The evolution of brain death criteria by the Harvard Ad-Hoc Committee Report has opened the door to understanding the importance of medical, legal and ethical challenges of organ donation in support of the growth of the transplant science. The possibility of organ donation from living donors has enhanced organ availability for patients with kidney failure. Modern inotropes and immunosuppression regimens have been critical to the success of other organ transplant procedures. However, the cornerstone of successful transplantation continues to be the appropriate selection, evaluation, preservation of organ tissues and the successful surgical procurement process to mitigate the impact of tissue ischemia and reperfusion.</p>
<p>In the multi-organ donor: a guide to selection, preservation and procurement, the art and science of organ donation and tissue preservation is examined. Through this authoritative text by leaders in the field, the editors provide a state of the art review of modern preservation techniques, patient selection and screening criteria, as well as best practices for multi-organ procurement. Information presented in the book will familiarize readers with the initial steps of determining organ availability which ultimately enables health care professionals to realize the extraordinary potential of successful multi-organ transplant procedures. This guide is intended to be a fundamental resource for students, residents, faculty and staff for all disciplines allied to health care delivery and organ donation.</p>
<p>About the Author:</p>
<p>Dr. Robert S. D. Higgins</p>
<p>Dr. Robert S. D. Higgins joined Johns Hopkins Medicine in July 2015 as the Surgeon-in-chief, the William Stewart Halsted Professor of Surgery and the Director of the Department of Surgery at the Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine. His scientific interests are broad and far-ranging, including health economics and policy, competency-based residency training, and racial disparities in post-transplant outcomes. He holds leadership positions in the Society of Thoracic Surgeons and the Society of Surgical Chairs; he has previously served as the president of the United Network for Organ Sharing and the Society of Black Academic Surgeons. He has authored over 150 scientific articles and book chapters.</p>
<p>Dr. Juan A. Samchez</p>
<p>Dr. Sanchez is currently Chair of the Department of Surgery at Ascension Saint Agnes Hospital in Baltimore and Associate Professor at the Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine. He has served as Assistant Professor at the University of Miami and Associate Professor at the University of Kentucky where he was Director of the Heart Transplant Program. His research interests have revolved around protecting the myocardium against ischemic damage and long-term organ preservation.</p>
<p>For more information, Please visit; <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681087566/">https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681087566/</ext-link></p>
</body>
</article>
