<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190329-007</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title>The seventh volume of Topics In Anti-cancer Research is now available</article-title>
</title-group>
<aff>
                <bold>Book: </bold>
                <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086279/">Topics in Anti-Cancer Research</ext-link>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 24-JAN-2019</aff>
<abstract>
<p>This book is by Prof. Dr. Atta-ur Rahman, and Dr. Khurshid Zaman, published on: November 30th, 2018.</p>
</abstract>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<break/>
<p>The book series offers readers an insight into current and future therapeutic approaches for the prevention of different types of cancers, synthesizing new anti-cancer agents, new patented compounds, targets and agents for cancer therapy as well as recent molecular and gene therapy research.</p>
<p>The topics covered in the seventh volume of this series include:</p>
<p>- The role of inflammation in chemotherapy-induced neuromuscular effects</p>
<p>- Advances in nutrigenomics and relevant anti-cancer patents</p>
<p>- Stimuli-responsive nanocarriers for on-demand anti-cancer drug release</p>
<p>- Harnessing biochemical mechanisms that control autophagy for treating esophageal cancer</p>
<break/>
<p><bold>About the Author:</bold></p>
<p><bold>Prof. Dr. Atta-ur Rahman</bold></p>
<p>Atta-ur-Rahman, Ph.D. in organic chemistry from Cambridge University (1968), has over 1080 international publications in several fields of organic chemistry including 751 research publications, 37 international patents, 69 chapters in books and 222 books published largely by major U.S. and European presses. He is the Editor-in-Chief of eight European Chemistry journals. He is Editor of the world&apos;s leading encyclopedic series of volumes on natural products, Studies in Natural Product Chemistry, 54 volumes of which have been published under his Editorship by Elsevier during the last two decades.</p>
<p><bold>Dr. Khurshid Zaman</bold></p>
<p>Dr. Khurshid Zaman is M.Phil. in Molecular Biology, Biochemistry and Biological Sciences from Quaid-e Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan. She has qualified Ph.D. in Organic Chemistry from H.E.J. Institute of Chemistry, Karachi, Pakistan. Some research work on Trace Element Analysis and Liver regeneration was carried out from Lund University Sweden during her Ph.D. She has done Post Doc. Research from Hamdard University in collaboration with H.E.J. Institute of Chemistry, Karachi, Pakistan and from Geneva, Switzerland in Tissue culture. She has published research papers, reviewers and edited a Book and eBooks. She was the Editor of Pakistan Journal of Scientific Research. She worked in Abbott Laboratories and PCSIR. Serving as a Director Patent, EiC and Executive Editor of Patent Journals at Bentham Science Publishers. Also, Editor of eBook Patent Series on Topics on Anti-Cancer Research. She is also a member of WAME and UNIDO Assessor in Laboratory Accreditation ISO/IEC 17025.</p>
<p>For more information please visit: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086279/">https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681086279/</ext-link></p>
</body>
</article>
