<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190402-011</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title>The fourth volume of Anti-obesity Drug Discovery and Development is now published</article-title>
</title-group>
<aff>
                <bold>Book: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681085586/">Anti-Obesity Drug Discovery and Development</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 15-FEB-2019</aff>
<abstract>
<p>This book is Edited by: Atta-ur-Rahman, M. Iqbal Choudhary, published on: December 14th, 2018.</p>
</abstract>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<break/>
<p>The incidence of obesity among populations in both the developing and the developed world has reached epidemic proportions. In response to this, efforts to control and treat obesity have also been vigorously pursued, ranging from activities focused on raising awareness about lifestyle changes to the discovery and development of safe and effective anti-obesity drugs. Anti-obesity Drug Discovery and Development is a book series focused on this very important area of healthcare research. Each volume presents insightful updates on pharmaceutical research and development for clinical researchers and healthcare professionals involved in obesity treatment programs.</p>
<p>Anti-obesity Drug Discovery and Development, the fourth volume of this series covers 6 reviews on anti-obesity treatment strategies including updates on obesity and cancer prevention through dietary modulation, the role of anti-obesity medications in polycystic ovary syndrome, potential anti-obesity strategies targeting mitochondria, calcium silicate based formulations for anti-obesity therapy, and the identification of obesity medications from natural products and plants.</p>
<break/>
<p><bold>About the Editors(s):</bold></p>
<p><bold>Prof. Dr. Atta-ur-Rahman</bold></p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Atta-ur-Rahman, Ph.D. in organic chemistry from Cambridge University (1968), has over 1080 international publications in several fields of organic chemistry including 751 research publications, 37 international patents, 69 chapters in books and 222 books published largely by major U.S. and European presses. He is the Editor-in-Chief of eight European Chemistry journals. He is Editor of the world&apos;s leading encyclopedic series of volumes on natural products, Studies in Natural Product Chemistry, 54 volumes of which have been published under his Editorship by Elsevier during the last two decades.</p>
<p><bold>Prof. Dr. M. Iqbal Choudhary</bold></p>
<p>Prof. Dr. M. Iqbal Choudhary is a Distinguish National Meritorious and Director at International Center for Chemical and Biological Sciences (H. E. J. Research Institute of Chemistry and Dr. Panjwani Center for Molecular Medicine and Drug Research). He has written and edited 68 books, most of which have been published in USA and Europe. He is also the author of over 1,018 research papers and chapters in top international science journals of the West, as well as 48 US patents. The cumulative impact factor of his publications is over 2,120. He has been among the most cited scientists in last five years with citations exceeding 23,000 (h-Index: 62). He is the Volume Editor of many international book series and journals. He has served as a visiting faculty in many prestigious universities of the world, including Cornell University (New York), Purdue University (Indiana), Pennsylvania State University (Pennsylvania), Scripps Institution of Oceanography (San Diego, California), The University Rhode Island (Rhode Island) and various top Universities.</p>
<p>For more information, please visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681085586/">https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681085586/</ext-link></p>
</body>
</article>
