<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190402-001</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title>Bentham Science launches animated abstracts -- A new exciting venture in publishing!</article-title>
</title-group>
<aff>
                <bold>Book: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/video.html">Current Advances in Developing Inhibitors of Bacterial Multidrug Efflux Pumps</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 25-FEB-2019</aff>
                
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<break/>
<p>Extend the scope and visibility of your research by creating an animated abstract. Bentham Science has collaborated with Focus Medica, one of the world&apos;s largest publishers of expert animated atlases and videos in medicine and science.</p>
<p>An animated abstract will help summarise the essential discoveries/ key findings of the authors&apos; published research or review article. Each professionally produced full-coloured animated abstract in video format (length 3 - 5 minutes) is accompanied by an English spoken or foreign language commentary. The animated abstract will be published online along with the published article.</p>
<p>Animated abstracts provide added value to published contentby means of a visual presentation using narration (in any language), audiovisual resources, graphs, flow diagrams, images and animation. Bentham Science is at the forefront of publishing offering authors such unique video abstracts.</p>
<p>Authors will be asked whether they wish to opt-in for this paid service, and if not, the article will be published without a video abstract. Animated abstracts are available as open access (free viewing) for maximum visibility and awareness toreaders at anytime, anywhere. The animated abstracts are licensed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International Public License (CC BY-NC-ND 4.0) <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link></p>
<p>For a sample of an animated abstract, please access here <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/video.html">http://www.eurekaselect.com/video.html</ext-link></p>
</body>
</article>
