<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
    <front>
        <journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <issn pub-type="ppub">
            </issn>
            <issn pub-type="epub">
            </issn>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
        <article-meta>
            <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190115-006</article-id>
            <title-group>
                <article-title>Treatment of Parkinson's disease: Separating hope from hype</article-title>
            </title-group>
            <aff id="aff1">
                <bold>Research Article: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/165253/article">Cellular, Molecular and Non-Pharmacological Therapeutic Advances for the Treatment of Parkinson's disease: Separating Hope from Hype</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 26-DEC-2018</aff>
            <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
                <year>
                </year>
            </pub-date>
            <volume>
            </volume>
            <issue>
            </issue>
            <history>
                <date date-type="released">
                    <day>26</day>
                    <month>12</month>
                    <year>2018</year>
                </date>
            </history>
            <permissions>
                <copyright-year>
                </copyright-year>
            </permissions>
            <abstract>
                <p>
                    <italic>The article by Dr. Alireza Mohammadi et al. is published in Current Gene Therapy, Volume 18, Issue 4, 2018</italic>
                </p>
            </abstract>
        </article-meta>
    </front>
    <body>
        <p>Parkinson&apos;s disease is a neurodegenerative disorder characterized by motor and nonmotor deficits majorly caused by the loss of dopaminergic cells in the Substantia Nigra pars compacta (SNc) as well as the destruction of nigrostriatal pathway. Despite the numerous advances in cutting-edge approaches for the treatment or prevention of PD, there still exists some obstacles that have incapacitated the definitive treatment of this disease.</p>
        <p>New therapeutic strategies have emerged over recent years to treat PD, including gene- and stem cell- based therapies, targeted delivery of neurotrophic factors, and brain stimulation techniques such as Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS), transcranial Direct Current Stimulation (tDCS), and Deep Brain Stimulation (DBS).</p>
        <p>The review covers various gene therapy strategies including Adeno-Associated Virus-Glutamic Acid Decarboxylase (AAV-GAD), AAV-Aromatic L-Amino Acid Decarboxylase (AAV-AADC), Lenti-AADC/Tyrosine Hydroxylase/Guanosine Triphosphate- Cyclohydrolase I (Lenti-AADC/TH/GTP-CH1), AAV-Neurturin (AAV-NRTN), &#x03B1;-Synuclein silencing, and PRKN gene delivery. The review also covers the advantages and disadvantages of these treatments along with the results of relevant trials. With many advances in treatments for PD, there still exist some hurdles that have resulted in treatment failure; the reasons for failure of treatment were described, with hope separated from hype.</p>
        <p>The article is Open Access till 31st January, 2019. To obtain the article please visit: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.eurekaselect.com/165253">http://www.eurekaselect.com/165253</ext-link></p>
    </body>
</article>
