<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
    <front>
        <journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
        <article-meta>
            <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190329-006</article-id>
            <title-group>
                <article-title>The second volume of Frontiers in Ceramic Science is now available</article-title>
            </title-group>
            <aff>
                <bold>Book: </bold>
                <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681087580/">Catalytic Materials for Hydrogen Production and Electro-oxidation Reactions</ext-link>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 22-JAN-2019</aff>
            <abstract>
                <p>This book is by Dr. Moisés R. Cesário, Dr. Daniel A. de Macedo, Dr. Cédric Gennequin &#x0026; Dr. Edmond Abi-Aad, published on: December 4th, 2018.</p>
            </abstract>
        </article-meta>
    </front>
    <body>
        <break/>
        
        <p>Catalytic Materials for Hydrogen Production and Electro-oxidation Reactions presents information about catalytic materials for hydrogen production and hydrogen valorization in electro-oxidation reactions. Chapters emphasize on materials for classical steam, CO2 sorption enhanced steam reforming and dry reforming for hydrogen production. The hydrogen electro-oxidation reaction in anodes of Solid Oxide Fuel Cells (SOFCs) is also explained. Chapters have been contributed by experts in industrial chemistry, adding a valuable perspective for readers. This volume is essential to chemical engineering researchers and industrial professionals interested in hydrogen production systems and the science behind the materials driving the reactions in key processes.</p>
        <break/>
        <p>
            <bold>About the Author:</bold>
        </p>
        <p>
            <bold>Dr. Moisés R. Cesario</bold>
        </p>
        <p>Mois&#x00E9;s R. Cesario has a Ph.D. degree in physicochemical sciences from the University of Strasbourg (France) in co-supervision with the Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (Brazil). Following a post-doctorate at the University of Aveiro (Portugal), he was an Assistant Professor and Researcher at the National Graduate School of Engineering and a researcher at the University of the Littoral Opal Coast (France). He currently works as a Researcher at the University of Upper Alsace (France). As a result of his work, he has authored articles published in journals and conference proceedings, patents, books and book chapters. His research interests include oxygen storage materials, SOx adsorbents, and nanomaterials for fuel cells and reforming reactions for hydrogen production.</p>
        <p>
            <bold>Dr. Daniel A. de Macedo</bold>
        </p>
        <p>Prof. Daniel Macedo has devoted the last decade of his academic career to the study and improvement of ceramic and composite materials for energy conversion in electrochemical devices. He is the author of several scientific papers published in conferences and journals of international circulation, book chapters, and patents. He is an adjunct professor at the Department of Materials Engineering of the Federal University of Para&#x00ED;ba (Brazil).</p>
        <p>
            <bold>Dr. Cédric Gennequin</bold>
        </p>
        <p>Cédric Gennequin is an Assistant Professor and researcher at the University of the Littoral Opal Coast (France). He has experience in the field of clean and renewable energy, specifically in the production of hydrogen for fuel cells via the valorization of biomass by catalytic reforming.</p>
        <p>
            <bold>Dr. Edmond Abi-Aad</bold>
        </p>
        <p>Edmond Abi-Aad is the First Vice-President and Full Professor/researcher at the University of the Littoral Opal Coast (France). He has experience in the field of clean and renewable energy, specifically in the production of hydrogen for fuel cells via the valorization of biomass by catalytic reforming/CO2 recovery.</p>
        <break/>
        <p>For more information please visit: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681087580/">https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681087580/</ext-link></p>
    </body>
</article>
