<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front>
<journal-meta>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">RT</journal-id>
            <journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Rec Trend</journal-id>
            <journal-title>Recent Trends</journal-title>
            <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Rec. Trend.</abbrev-journal-title>
            <publisher>
                <publisher-name>Bentham Science Publishers</publisher-name>
            </publisher>
        </journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">RT-20190402-006</article-id>
<title-group>
<article-title>Development of Pharmaceutical Agent for the Treatment of Diabetes &#x0026; Obesity</article-title>
</title-group>
<aff>
                <bold>Book: </bold>
                <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681084459/">Frontiers in Clinical Drug Research - Diabetes and Obesity</uri>
            </aff>
            <aff>
                <bold>Public Release:</bold> 15-FEB-2019</aff>
<abstract>
<p>This book is Edited by: Atta-ur-Rahman, published on: January 18, 2019</p>
</abstract>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<break/>
<p>The scope of the eBook series covers a range of topics including the medicinal chemistry, pharmacology, molecular biology and biochemistry of natural and synthetic drugs affecting endocrine and metabolic processes linked with diabetes and obesity. Reviews in this series also include research on specific receptor targets and pre-clinical / clinical findings on novel pharmaceutical agents. Frontiers in Clinical Drug Research - Diabetes and Obesity is a valuable resource for pharmaceutical scientists and postgraduate students seeking updated and critically important information for developing clinical trials and devising research plans in the field of diabetes and obesity research.</p>
<p>The fourth volume of this series features 7 chapters:</p>
<p>Pharmacologic Obesity Treatment</p>
<p>Interplay Between Bile Acid and GLP-1 Receptor Agonist Signaling Informs the Design of Drugs to Combat Obesity and its Metabolic Complications</p>
<p>Sodium-Glucose Co-Transporters Inhibitors for Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</p>
<p>The Effects of Traditional Chinese Medicine on Inflammatory Cytokines in Diabetic Nephropathy</p>
<p>Through the Perspective of Histology - The Alzheimer&apos;s Disease Promotion by Obesity and Glucose Metabolism: Type 3 Diabetes</p>
<p>Pharmacological Mechanism of PPAR&#x03B3; Ratio in Diabetes and Obesity</p>
<p>Hydrogen Sulfide and Carbohydrate Metabolism</p>
<break/>
<p><bold>About the Editor(s):</bold></p>
<p><bold>Prof. Dr. Atta-ur-Rahman</bold></p>
<p>Prof. Dr. Atta-ur-Rahman, Ph.D. in organic chemistry from Cambridge University (1968), has over 1080 international publications in several fields of organic chemistry including 751 research publications, 37 international patents, 69 chapters in books and 222 books published largely by major U.S. and European presses. He is the Editor-in-Chief of eight European Chemistry journals. He is Editor of the world&apos;s leading encyclopedic series of volumes on natural products, Studies in Natural Product Chemistry, 54 volumes of which have been published under his Editorship by Elsevier during the last two decades. For more information please visit, <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681084459/">https://ebooks.benthamscience.com/book/9781681084459/</ext-link></p>
</body>
</article>
